<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Strategy Archives - Blog | Max Quinn</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/strategy/feed/?simply_static_page=157" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/strategy/</link>
	<description>Freelance Digital Product Designer</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 10:23:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>3: Pace layering</title>
		<link>/pace-layering/</link>
					<comments>/pace-layering/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Max]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 09:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Product]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=81</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The ability to grow and adapt while remaining on a continuous and non-destructive trajectory is a goal as old as time. It is something the systems around us have been forced to learn and embed within themselves &#8211; as the world spun through ice ages and natural disasters, as our species developed language or moved [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/pace-layering/">3: Pace layering</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="">Blog | Max Quinn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The ability to grow and adapt while remaining on a continuous and non-destructive trajectory is a goal as old as time. It is something the systems around us have been forced to learn and embed within themselves &#8211; as the world spun through ice ages and natural disasters, as our species developed language or moved into the industrial age.</p>



<p>It is often said that the ability to learn is the most important skill one can possess, and that’s something that applies just as much to giant, complex systems as it does to the individual. It is what allows them to survive and thrive. Essential to this is ability to learn is experimentation &#8211; trialing new concepts and learning from them. From rainforest ecosystems developing to early humans grunting to communicate their desires, the introduction of a small new idea has the power to fundamentally change how systems as massive as our planet or our civilisation function.</p>



<p>A willingness to be open to new ideas is what leads to new discoveries. But in a world where many ideas will end in failure, that same willingness could easily lead a system down destructive paths if left unchecked. History is full of what could be considered failed experiments &#8211; extinct species, languages and empires. Many of them, the Roman empire for example, were great successes for a long time and left many important ideas and skills that still benefit the system of civilisation today. Many others were brief footnotes or catastrophic failures, often rejected by the repulsed system through force.</p>



<p>Importantly in both cases, the system is willing to move on &#8211; to avoid diminishing growth or to course correct its trajectory. The ability of these incredible complex systems to experiment and advance while remaining relatively stable is where an interesting concept lies: <em>Pace Layering</em>.</p>



<p></p>



<h3 id="what-is-pace-layering">What is pace layering?</h3>



<p>A blueprint for how systems learn, Pace Layering (a concept I came across in Stewart Brand’s <a href="https://jods.mitpress.mit.edu/pub/issue3-brand/release/2">excellent article on the subject</a>) proposes that systems are built of varying layers. </p>



<p>The inner-most of these are the most slow moving and change only on long timeframes. The outer layers move quickly and change constantly. These outer layers are where experimentation happens, they are constantly adapting to their environment and try new things with relative freedom.</p>



<p>The layer immediately below learns from them, but due to its slower pace is somewhat resistant to. Only changes that stand the test of time in outer layers are absorbed through the inner layers, so the system evolves while remaining relatively true to its inner-most values, goals and knowledge. It is at once adaptable and robust.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="172" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-layerspeed-1024x172.png" alt="" class="wp-image-95" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-layerspeed-1024x172.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-layerspeed-300x50.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-layerspeed-768x129.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-layerspeed.png 1288w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>As Brand explains, the fast and slow layers compliment each other excellently in a balanced system&#8230;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table" style="font-size:18px"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Fast&#8230;</strong></td><td><strong>Slow&#8230;</strong></td></tr><tr><td>learns</td><td>remembers</td></tr><tr><td>proposes</td><td>disposes</td></tr><tr><td>is discontinuous</td><td>is continuous</td></tr><tr><td>instructs slow by accrued innovation and occasional revolution</td><td>controls fast by constraint and constancy</td></tr><tr><td>gets all of our attention</td><td>has all the power</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>To take the structure of a civilisation as an example, he proposes 6 layers…</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-civilisationlayers-1024x576.png" alt="" class="wp-image-93" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-civilisationlayers-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-civilisationlayers-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-civilisationlayers-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-civilisationlayers.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Fashion (which I take to include media and art) &#8211; the outer-most layer &#8211; is ruthlessly experimental. It trials ideas constantly and moves on from them quickly. Commerce below this adapts to include the most successful of these ideas, which in turn affects infrastructure and so on. The inner-most layers are resistant to change and enforce constraints on those above them &#8211; nature’s inability to accept our treatment of it being an illustration of this. In that way, layers need to respect the existence and pace of those above and below them &#8211; accepting their constraints and being open to their learnings.</p>



<p>Another benefit of this system is its ability to absorb shocks. The faster moving, outer layers react and accommodate change, allowing the system to bend rather than break under stress and the inner layers to remain unaffected.</p>



<p></p>



<h3 id="how-can-we-apply-this-to-company-strategy">How can we apply this to company strategy?</h3>



<p>As well as applying to the most gigantic systems, this is a concept that resonates just as strongly in smaller ones. On an individual level for example, we have a system of layers from our inner-most biology and basic needs through our intellectual capacity, values and interests to our fashions, jobs and daily activities. We go through our lives trialling things on our outer layers which inform who we eventually become.</p>



<p>The same can be said of companies. Whether we are aware of it or not, a system such as this already exists in the operation of a company. Our ability to more deeply understand this system should effect our effectiveness in considering and acting upon it.</p>



<p>From the perspective of a design strategist, I would propose six layers that form a company&#8230;</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-companylayers-1024x576.png" alt="" class="wp-image-94" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-companylayers-1024x576.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-companylayers-300x169.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-companylayers-768x432.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-companylayers.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table" style="font-size:18px"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Mission</strong></td></tr><tr><td>The highest level goal of a company. This is the organisations reason to exist, the key beliefs that led to its formation.<br><br>Some may be purely based on business and market needs &#8211; such as Disney’s ‘<em>To be one of the world’s leading producers and providers of entertainment and information’ &#8211;</em> while others may be more social &#8211; such as Tesla’s &#8216;<em>to accelerate the world&#8217;s transition to sustainable energy’</em>.<br><br>They very rarely change, if ever, and define the company’s market, focus and aims.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table" style="font-size:18px"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Vision</strong></td></tr><tr><td>At a slightly higher level, the vision is how the company plans to make their mission happen. Whether it’s by creating children’s films or selling electric vehicles, it contains what needs to happen for the company to move towards its mission in the near future.<br><br>Importantly, it is more adaptable than mission, as the route to achieving the ultimate goal is likely to change with an ever-moving world and market. In their goal of transitioning the world to sustainable energy for example, Tesla may focus their vision on cars now but later down the line may offer a full-suite electric mobility subscription or shift their core focus to aviation</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table" style="font-size:18px"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Model</strong></td></tr><tr><td>The layer of business strategy, a company model aims to match its vision to market needs. To provide products that achieve its vision in a way the market is willing to consume them and at a rate that market is willing to pay.<br><br>It may at one time be about manufacturing and selling cars directly to consumers, at another be focused on providing services to businesses or eventually converting infrastructure. There are often many business models being trialled or successfully running within a company’s overall model, and the success or failure of these will influence the company vision over time.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table" style="font-size:18px"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong><strong>Brand</strong></strong></td></tr><tr><td>Above the model, a brand contains the core tenets of the way a company displays itself to the world. It is the personality of a company &#8211; how it communicates, looks, advertises and engages with the systems around it.<br><br>It adapts to changing trends and markets as well as to the learnings of the products and marketing above it. Absorbing changes in its audience, these learnings might be fed down into the model in order to more effectively provide for these new circumstances.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table" style="font-size:18px"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong><strong>Product</strong></strong></td></tr><tr><td>The products a company will offer are a result of the layers below them &#8211; what the company is trying to achieve, the business around doing this and the personality of the company. They are experimented upon, evolved and adapted to the market with regularity.<br><br>New cars are launched for new audiences, new features are trialled and abandoned, upsell offerings are tweaked. Their success is evaluated (see BCG’s <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/marketing-planning/marketing-models/use-bcg-matrix/">Portfolio Matrix</a> for example) and the successes are absorbed further into brand and model while the failures are rejected or iterated upon.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table" style="font-size:18px"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong><strong><strong>Marketing &amp; sales</strong></strong></strong></td></tr><tr><td>At the outermost layer, a company will engage with its audience or potential audience in a multitude of ways. From advertising and mailing lists to focus groups and outbound sales, marketing will move incredibly rapidly to test audiences, ideas and messaging. It will constantly engage with the market and absorb the multitude of learnings that come from this. It may even test products, brand changes and models before they exist.<br><br>It is the layer of the now, latching onto meme trends and current events to amplify its voice. Due to its transient nature, few of these experiments and changes are likely to move deeply down the company’s layers, but over time some of them come to influence the deepest tenets of a company’s existence.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>As in the system of civilisation, learnings and adaptations trickle down through these layers slowly and many do not move deeper into the system at all&#8230;</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="235" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-movingexperiments-1024x235.png" alt="" class="wp-image-96" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-movingexperiments-1024x235.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-movingexperiments-300x69.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-movingexperiments-768x176.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/02/illu-movingexperiments.png 1288w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<h3 id="what-can-we-learn-from-this">What can we learn from this?</h3>



<p>This is an empowering system for the ‘fail fast’ age of corporate strategy we are in. It allows marketing and product to move quickly and trial ideas free in the knowledge that their failures will not be absorbed too deeply through the company. By considering the system, we can allow it to do its job &#8211; that of protecting our deepest values and goals while allowing the company as a whole to adapt to top level and external influences.</p>



<p>It also provides a model for learning, a prompt for layers and company functions to consider the needs, constraints and successes of others.</p>



<p>Inner layers are encouraged to continuously absorb and analyse the successes and failures above them. A digital dashboard product may adapt it’s language based on marketing learnings above it, which might feed into the underlying brand tone of voice and eventually trigger a change in model &#8211; away from a pricing structure that enables ‘power’ and towards one that enables ‘convenience’ for example.</p>



<p>Outer layers are empowered to experiment with relative freedom but also encouraged to consider the constraints that exist below them &#8211; the audiences that may be out of bounds based on the company’s pricing model or the bad practices that would be in opposition to it’s brand values.</p>



<p>What’s more, a company can be absorbent of shocks. From small events such as a cultural wave that marketing rides without impacting the company brand to black swan events such as a global pandemic that may impact a company’s model without changing it’s vision and mission, the system can adapt to just the right level to survive negative changes and further thrive through those that contain opportunities.</p>



<p>As Brand puts it&#8230;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p><em>The total effect of the pace layers is that they provide a many-leveled corrective, stabilizing feedback throughout the system.&nbsp;It is precisely in the apparent contradictions between the pace layers that civilization finds its surest health.</em></p><cite>Stewart Brand – <a href="https://jods.mitpress.mit.edu/pub/issue3-brand/release/2">Pace Layering: How complex systems learn and keep learning</a></cite></blockquote></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table" style="font-size:14px"><table><tbody><tr><td><em><strong>Footnote: </strong>For the wider reader, it is important to note that &#8216;Pace Layering&#8217; is a concept that has separately been adapted as a structure for IT governance. It bares some similarities to what I outline above but has many fundamental differences and should not be conflated with what I aim to discuss.</em></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<div id="mc_embed_signup">
<h3>Sign up for articles straight to your inbox</h3>
<form action="https://maxjquinn.us16.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=91299ba70dc87e5deb25816bd&amp;id=7c26487202" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank" novalidate="">
    <div id="mc_embed_signup_scroll">
	
<div class="mc-field-group">
	<input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="required email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="Enter your email">
</div>
	<div id="mce-responses" class="clear">
		<div class="response" id="mce-error-response" style="display:none"></div>
		<div class="response" id="mce-success-response" style="display:none"></div>
	</div>    <!-- real people should not fill this in and expect good things - do not remove this or risk form bot signups-->
    <div style="position: absolute; left: -5000px;" aria-hidden="true"><input type="text" name="b_91299ba70dc87e5deb25816bd_7c26487202" tabindex="-1" value=""></div>
    <div class="clear"><input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button button--submit"></div>
    </div>
</form>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/pace-layering/">3: Pace layering</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="">Blog | Max Quinn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/pace-layering/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2: Building a learning machine</title>
		<link>/building-a-learning-machine-part-1/</link>
					<comments>/building-a-learning-machine-part-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Max]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 18:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Product]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=36</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the startup world, one of the most common tropes is the idea of learning from users. Gathering insight and implementing it into your product is essential to building the right thing, and building it well. The problem? It&#8217;s often much harder to do than it sounds, particularly in early stage companies moving quickly with [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/building-a-learning-machine-part-1/">2: Building a learning machine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="">Blog | Max Quinn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the startup world, one of the most common tropes is the idea of learning from users. Gathering insight and implementing it into your product is essential to building the right thing, and building it well. The problem? It&#8217;s often much harder to do than it sounds, particularly in early stage companies moving quickly with little process and even less resource.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="702" height="79" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/illu-insightquestioning.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-63"/></figure>



<p>Having worked in a wide range of startups worldwide, I&#8217;ve noticed a few common themes that prevent companies from really leveraging user insight&#8230;</p>



<p></p>



<h3>Problem 1: Effort &amp; Resource</h3>



<p>Where moving quickly is essential, everything becomes about balancing resource and effort with quality or scope. For that reason, a large amount of strategy work in early stage companies boils down to a simple question: What is good enough?</p>



<p>ie: What does a minimum viable product need to do? How polished does our brand need to be? How scalable should our engineering processes be? etc.</p>



<p>Understanding users is no different, and it&#8217;s a hard balance to strike. The question becomes: When do we know enough about users to have confidence in our general direction?</p>



<p>To simplify, there are generally two schools of thought&#8230;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><h4>Design Thinking</h4></td><td><h4>Lean startup</h4></td></tr><tr><td>Often advocated by design and research agencies, the type of research implemented in effective design thinking involves in depth, largely up front research.</td><td>Advocates of the lean startup aim to ship products as quickly as possible and then learn from them in the wild. They live by the mantra of &#8216;move fast and break things&#8217;.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Methods:</strong> Interviews and focus groups, ethnographic studies, prototype testing, co-designing with users, task diaries, surveys.</td><td><strong>Methods:</strong> Product analytics, metric tracking, user surveys, ad-hoc customer learnings, user testing, NPS score.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Pros:</strong> In depth understanding. Discover what to build, not just how.</td><td><strong>Pros:</strong> Beat competitors to market. Learn from real, active users.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Cons:</strong> Time and effort. Expertise required. Insights generated in bulk after a long timeframe. </td><td><strong>Cons:</strong> Risk building the wrong things or for the wrong people. Reduce effectiveness of design. Create product debt.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>On one end of the scale, design research is in depth and can provide more confidence in decisions, but is expensive, cumbersome and to product people looks a lot like &#8216;the dreaded waterfall&#8217;. On the other, a narrative based on speed has lowered the bar to a dangerous level where companies risk building the wrong things ineffectively. What&#8217;s more, the &#8216;learn&#8217; phase too often gets lost in the melee of running a live product.</p>



<p></p>



<h3>Problem 2: The Insight → Product Gap</h3>



<p>All too often in both of the above approaches, the process of collecting learnings and generating insights stops there. People sit back with a smile on their face, pleased at developing all this insight and doing what they&#8217;ve read startups should do. Then they store their learnings in a document buried on a drive somewhere and promptly forget about them. Or even worse, they are stored only in people&#8217;s heads.</p>



<p>Companies often seem to be lacking a clear process of how to actually incorporate learnings into product development and ensure they have a measurable impact. Without this, it&#8217;s hard to tie them to business goals and product metrics, or know how to prioritise them</p>



<p>What&#8217;s more, there&#8217;s also a gap in the other direction. Learning is too often haphazard and self directed, rather than aimed at specific product goals and issues. This misses the fact that learning should be a cyclical process, one that aims for constant growth of understanding and refinement of product. It should also be as much about understanding how well you are solving problems or taking opportunities as it is about gathering the learnings you need to do those things.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="637" height="378" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/illu-researchproductgap.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-65"/></figure>



<p></p>



<h3>Problem 3: The narrow lens</h3>



<p>When talking about generating product insights, different team members often focus on different things. Designers focus on learning from users, product managers on analytics, business leads on business goals, developers on engineering metrics such as uptime, load time etc.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s ok, we have specialism for a reason. The problem comes when these are looked at too separately, with completely different work-streams and systems. It makes it difficult to see the connections between them all and even more difficult to prioritise them. They end up battling with each other for space in a product&#8217;s roadmap, rather than building upon each other in harmony.</p>



<p>To be clear, all of these approaches can generate great and equally important insights. If looked at together, they&#8217;re also often much more connected than they first appear to be.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="253" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/illu-blockage.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-66"/></figure>



<p></p>



<h3>Introducing the learning machine</h3>



<p>As a product design &amp; strategy consultant, the most valuable work I&#8217;ve done in companies has been all about trying to solve these problems. It&#8217;s led me to develop what I call <em>The Learning Machine,</em> a framework that aims to develop a process and culture of both learning, action and measurement within a company or product team.</p>



<p>It has the following goals and benefits&#8230;</p>



<ol><li><strong>Input agnostic<br></strong>Combine inputs from a wide range of sources and data types, particularly those that are already generating useful (but often unused) data<br></li><li><strong>Agile<br></strong>Provide an agile process that is constantly generating actionable insights<br></li><li><strong>Connected<br></strong>Ensure insights move into the product development process in a logical way<br></li><li><strong>Cyclical<br></strong>Provide a cyclical system that creates a framework for digging deeper into learnings and re-evaluating them after product improvements<br></li><li><strong>Analytical<br></strong>Provide a framework for measuring the impact of our actions</li></ol>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="347" src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/illu-condensedlearning.svg" alt="" class="wp-image-73"/></figure>



<p>The learning machine is a system based around gathering learnings, distilling the patterns in them to uncover what&#8217;s important, and then finding ways we can act on them and measuring the effectiveness of those actions. Over the course of my working life it&#8217;s become an all encompassing framework for looking at the development of products.</p>



<p>It combines elements of design, product strategy and business to move away from the concept of purely &#8216;user centricity&#8217; and towards the wider idea of &#8216;insight centricity&#8217; &#8211; the difference being that useful insights can come from lots of different places.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s a step by step process to show how this can actually be implemented on the ground in fast moving companies, particularly in the world of early stage startups.</p>



<p></p>



<h3>What to expect from this series</h3>



<p style="padding:0px;">Over the next two posts in this series, I&#8217;ll cover the following things:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><h4>Part 2: Generating insights</h4></td></tr><tr><td><strong>1. Collecting &amp; organising learning<br></strong>Where to look for learnings and how to manage a large amount of data from different sources.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2. <strong>Generating insights<br></strong></strong>How to move from data to useful insight.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>3. Prioritising insights<br></strong>How to prioritise insights and understand where to focus.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><h4>Part 3: Taking action &amp; measuring effect</h4></td></tr><tr><td><strong>1. Develop hypothesis<br></strong>How to start defining the action that an insight leads to</td></tr><tr><td><strong>2. Prioritise hypothesis<br></strong>How to prioritise the multiple actions you could take</td></tr><tr><td><strong>3. Evaluation &amp; continuation<br></strong>How to know if you&#8217;re moving the needle and what to do next</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>It&#8217;s important to note I will be spending very little time (if any) on software and tools. This is a system of thinking that can be implemented using many tool-stacks, dependent on the individual and company preference. Instead, this series will encourage you to think about products in a new way and understand the practical process to implement this thinking.</p>



<p>With that in mind, sign up below to be notified when I publish <em>Part 2: Generating Insights</em>.</p>



<div id="mc_embed_signup">
<h3>Sign up for articles straight to your inbox</h3>
<form action="https://maxjquinn.us16.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=91299ba70dc87e5deb25816bd&amp;id=7c26487202" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank" novalidate="">
    <div id="mc_embed_signup_scroll">
	
<div class="mc-field-group">
	<input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="required email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="Enter your email">
</div>
	<div id="mce-responses" class="clear">
		<div class="response" id="mce-error-response" style="display:none"></div>
		<div class="response" id="mce-success-response" style="display:none"></div>
	</div>    <!-- real people should not fill this in and expect good things - do not remove this or risk form bot signups-->
    <div style="position: absolute; left: -5000px;" aria-hidden="true"><input type="text" name="b_91299ba70dc87e5deb25816bd_7c26487202" tabindex="-1" value=""></div>
    <div class="clear"><input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button button--submit"></div>
    </div>
</form>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/building-a-learning-machine-part-1/">2: Building a learning machine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="">Blog | Max Quinn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/building-a-learning-machine-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>1: Regnosis</title>
		<link>/regnosis/</link>
					<comments>/regnosis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Max]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 17:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Futurism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Product]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Futurist is a job title shrouded in mystery. In short, it&#8217;s the study of trends in an effort to predict the future. It&#8217;s something everyone does to an extent, whether consciously or subconsciously. From the small decisions of when to have a barbecue during an English summer right up to company decisions of what markets [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/regnosis/">1: Regnosis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="">Blog | Max Quinn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>Futurist</em> is a job title shrouded in mystery. In short, it&#8217;s the study of trends in an effort to predict the future. It&#8217;s something everyone does to an extent, whether consciously or subconsciously. From the small decisions of when to have a barbecue during an English summer right up to company decisions of what markets to go after and what products to build.</p>



<p>For product managers, strategists and designers it&#8217;s even more essential to have an idea of how the world might change, it&#8217;s what enables us to build products for it. But while we all think loosely about what the future might hold, it&#8217;s rare that we really dedicate the time and effort to create diligent predictions. What&#8217;s more, like a designer with no knowledge of the human interface guidelines or a product manager trying to prioritise without data, we operate without frameworks that can help us synthesise information and understand our thoughts.</p>



<p>As such, the term <em>futurism</em> still comes with an intimidating cloak of blade-runner esque cool. So what do these mystic people know that the rest of us don&#8217;t, what enables them to be so good at predicting the future that they can make a job title out of it? Well, perhaps the difference between lay-people and practitioners is no different to many other fields: focused effort, tools and structure. </p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h3>Enter &#8216;Regnosis&#8217;&#8230;</h3>



<p>One of those tools for thinking about the future is the idea of Regnosis, something I came across in the work of German trend forecaster <a href="https://www.horx.com/">Matthias Horx</a>. While a traditional prognosis looks forward, from the present to the future, a regnosis takes a somewhat counter intuitive approach. It looks backwards, <em>from</em> the future.</p>



<p>If we are to take a date in the future, say a year from now, and metaphorically position ourselves there, how will today look? What will we be desperate to tell our past selves? What will have surprised us most in the last year?</p>



<p>Thinking into the future can be a daunting task, cripplingly so. But by placing ourselves in the future to start with, we create a more natural bridge between today and tomorrow. As Horx puts it, we &#8220;<em>form a loop of knowledge in which we include ourselves and our inner change in the future&#8230; If you do it right, something like future intelligence is created.&#8221;</em></p>



<p>This bridge, and the inclusion of our &#8216;inner change&#8217;, helps us take a different view. Rather than be paralysed by problems, we take a view on how they effected us or what change they instigated. Rather than just uncover opportunities, we take a view of what we gained from them.</p>



<p>Try it for a minute. Ask yourself the question: <em>If I was looking back from a year today, what would have surprised me in the last year?</em> You may notice that your answers are somewhat different to if you had asked yourself simply what will surprise you the next year. Perhaps problems seem more surmountable &#8211; our experience of looking forwards shows us that there will always be hurdles, but our experience of looking backwards shows us that we have always navigated them with reasonable success. Perhaps what comes to mind is completely different.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h3>So how can we use this in practice?</h3>



<p>As product people, we can apply Regnosis to make more diligent predictions, spot issues or opportunities we wouldn&#8217;t have otherwise and prioritise more effectively</p>



<p><strong>To focus strategy discussions</strong>, try casting your mind into various futures. One might be the dream scenario, your company has achieved all of it&#8217;s growth targets and is quickly becoming a market leader. Another might be a nightmare scenario, you&#8217;ve struggled to find product market fit and are quickly burning your capital. In both cases, what has surprised you? What&#8217;s had to happen to make those outcomes possible? For the ideal scenario, these are the things you need to ensure you are positioned to make the most of. For the nightmare scenario, these are the things you need to work around.</p>



<p><strong>To improve execution</strong>, try applying it to upcoming projects or features. Again, take an ideal scenario; the project has been completed and is a great success. And then try a nightmare scenario, the project hit insurmountable blockers or didn&#8217;t achieve it&#8217;s purpose. You can use these answers to uncover edge cases, implementation issues and risky dependencies that must be accounted for or even replaced.</p>



<p><strong>To improve our predictions.</strong> An essential part of making predictions of this nature is to check their accuracy, learn from failures and analyse patterns. We can do this by using the exact same questions. Set yourself up for success by looking at trends of the past: what has surprised you most in the last year? How about the year before that? And when you reach your eventual future, how do the results differ from your predictions? Only by asking these questions regularly, both before the fact and afterwards, can we start to get better at predicting the future. As well as kick-offs and strategic workshops, use them as part of retro&#8217;s and post-mortems to bring structure to your discussion, test your original predictions and uncover common patterns.</p>



<p>The novelty of the exercise, and the core question it poses, frees up our minds in a way that enables us to think differently, while still providing enough structure to create synthesised results that a team can rally around. And the regularity with which we can carry it out provides the kind of evolving log &#8211; of predictions we made and the realities that came to be &#8211; that is essential for pattern recognition.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>I&#8217;m sure this is only one of many tools in a true futurist&#8217;s locker, and it&#8217;s no silver bullet &#8211; you still need to do the thinking and balance it with other methods. But it&#8217;s one that provides a new lens with which to think about the direction of your product or company and the effectiveness of your execution. People often say there&#8217;s no accounting for experience, but all too often we meander through that experience without learning from it. The structure and focused effort of tools such as regnosis can help supercharge the relationship between experience and effectiveness.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/regnosis/">1: Regnosis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="">Blog | Max Quinn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/regnosis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
